<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://plateofplants.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://plateofplants.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-12-19T23:47:09-05:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/</id><title>Plate of Plants</title><subtitle>Making plant based cooking simple. Learn to take your vegetables from garden to gourmet. Tons of free vegan recipes and tips!</subtitle><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><entry><title>Gingerbread Cookies</title><link href="http://plateofplants.com/gingerbread-cookies" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gingerbread Cookies" /><published>2016-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/gingerbread-cookies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://plateofplants.com/gingerbread-cookies">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/gingerbread-cookies/ingredients-d08c9ca106a6f777622509aa7baa1030c0c9d1cddc6c60addc33de2feeddbeea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ingredients for healthy, vegan gingerbread cookies.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/gingerbread-cookies/cut-cookies-6088fdca5a102c70a85908d137bcf279d9ddfc89357a562c1dc9a95284eb7ccf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Healthy vegan gingerbread cookies.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/gingerbread-cookies/cut-out-cookies-863bd5b6e8803b2611a07b2461ea886643865d674078a5b4e6a839ab27d9bcbf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Healthy vegan gingerbread cookies.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/gingerbread-cookies/with-plant-milk-ca419c31fd985b1921a0a15914b8955ae46d3570c9d3178905eac70eaece339a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Healthy vegan gingerbread cookies.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/gingerbread-cookies/dipped-720530a58b3f505b397da3b59bcc483a51d8631612c530291dd51734be71ea09.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Healthy vegan gingerbread cookies.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The holidays are such a fun time of year. So many of my favorite traditions seem to revolve around food. That can make it really difficult to stay true to your healthy eating habits. One of the hardest things for me to avoid are sweets. There are cookies and candies everywhere. I knew I needed to make my own so I could be sure they were made with ingredients I want to eat, and none I don’t. Plus, I’m a sucker for traditions, so nothing was going to stop me from making Christmas cookies. I was determined to make a batch of cookies that I am proud of. These are the cookies I came up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some important things to keep in mind while making this recipe would be to make sure you refrigerate your dough for at least 4 hours before rolling it. You also want to keep the dough covered and cool at all times. Keeping the dough covered makes sure it won’t dry out while you aren’t using it. Keeping it cool helps the dough be less sticky when it is rolled out, and it makes it easier to work with. Be sure to return the covered bowl of dough to the fridge when you are rolling out the other portions. When rolling out the dough you want to be sure you are placing it on a well floured surface so your dough doesn’t stick. With these tips your cookies will turn out perfect!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These gingerbread cookies are packed full of health benefits. Yes, you read that sentence correctly. Molasses is full minerals such as iron, calcium, magnesium, and vitamin B6. Ginger is an anti-inflammatory and can help with everything from a sore throat to an upset stomach. Cinnamon helps lower blood sugar and can prevent tooth decay. These cookies are also made without oil or sugar. They are part of a whole food, plant-based diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give your family and friends cookies that they can enjoy without guilt. This recipe spreads good health to all those you love. If you tried this recipe, let me know in the comments below. Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gingerbread-cookies&quot;&gt;Gingerbread Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe by: Hannah&lt;br /&gt;
Serves: 2 dozen&lt;br /&gt;
Prep time: 15 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Cook time: 10 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Total time: 4 hours, 25 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
This is a whole food, plant-based vegan recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup applesauce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup molasses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 cup whole wheat flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 cup unbleached flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 tsp ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp cloves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix together applesauce, syrup, molasses, and vanilla in a large bowl. Add baking powder, baking soda, cinnamon, ginger, nutmeg, cloves, and salt. Stir until thoroughly mixed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start slowly adding flour until soft dough forms. When you can’t stir anymore, remove from bowl and knead the rest of the flour in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return to bowl and refrigerate at least 4 hours, preferably overnight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350°&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roll out dough on a floured surface (divide into quarters, roll out one quarter at a time), and cut with your favorite cookie cutters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place cookies on parchment lined cookie sheet and bake for 10-12 minutes. Remove from oven and let cool. Store in an airtight container for up to 7 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Butternut Squash Soup</title><link href="http://plateofplants.com/butternut-squash-soup" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Butternut Squash Soup" /><published>2016-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/butternut-squash-soup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://plateofplants.com/butternut-squash-soup">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/butternut-squash-soup/ingredients-b82710c14b108006d6b5c2c445b84eb4d267abdc17eeaade783911eb8c4d59ca.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ingredients for butternut squash soup.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/butternut-squash-soup/angled-veiw-853419b0d67c5ab15dfff864c2427a8461204c7925d05d78fc640f8f240888a8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Whole food, plant-based butternut squash soup.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/butternut-squash-soup/two-bowls-f627909e195e90dec40ac447ec765aec2e43a1a931a2b5344f3ae950261467b8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Whole food, plant-based butternut squash soup.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/butternut-squash-soup/thumbnail-d1d8205ad6cda56511e8c9e24a0362093f4af1a3e8b3345435f27675fd77e428.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Whole food, plant-based butternut squash soup.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Butternut squash soup was something I used to buy at the store. That was until I realized just how easy it was to make myself at home. It basically requires enough skill to cut vegetables and operate a blender. Plus, when you make it yourself you can choose to flavor it any way you want. This recipe is pretty basic and could definitely take on some holiday spices this time of year. Cinnamon and nutmeg both pair well with squash and would make a lovely addition to this basic recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This soup is perfect for those who cook without oil. When you add onions into a hot pan they create their own moisture and do not stick to the pan. If you have bad luck though, and your onions are sticking, you can just add a little bit of water to the pan and stir them around. The water will become steam soon enough and your recipe will turn out perfect!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This soup would also be great to make for anyone who has a cold. Onions are antiviral. Garlic is an extremely powerful healer when eaten raw. In this recipe, the garlic is cooked which means most of the healing power is gone. So if you have a cold that you are trying to get rid of try munching on a clove of raw garlic while you are cooking. It won’t be pleasant, but you will be feeling better before you know it. Ginger also has healing power as an anti-inflammatory, so it will help with sore throats. The butternut squash is packed full of potassium, vitamin C, and vitamin A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ingredients in this recipes mean it is food you can be proud of. You can serve this food to your friends and family knowing this soup will have a positive impact on their health. Taking the time to cook food that nourishes your body will always be worth it in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoyed this recipe, let me know in the comments below. Don’t forget to subscribe so you never miss a recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;butternut-squash-soup&quot;&gt;Butternut Squash Soup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe by: Hannah&lt;br /&gt;
Serves: 4&lt;br /&gt;
Prep time: 5 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Cook time: 20 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Total time: 25 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
This is a whole food, plant-based vegan recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large butternut squash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp ginger, grated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4-5 cups vegetable broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pepitas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peel the squash, scoop out the seeds, and cut into 1 inch cubes. Place cubes in steamer over medium heat and cook until extremely soft, 10-12 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat a large pot over medium heat. Once hot, add onion and cook 3-5 minutes, until softened. Next add minced garlic and grated ginger and cook another 2 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add cooked squash,  4 cups broth, and the contents of your pot to a blender and blend on high speed until soup is creamy. If the consistency is too thick, keep adding broth until it is to your liking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour the soup back into the pot and heat until simmering. Season with salt and pepper. Ladle into bowls and garnish with pepitas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Gardener’s Pie</title><link href="http://plateofplants.com/gardeners-pie" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gardener&#39;s Pie" /><published>2016-12-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/gardeners-pie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://plateofplants.com/gardeners-pie">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/gardeners-pie/ingredients-97129cf86c9eadb56f13c0d6d906007dd1c531acf667a6f02aea9e3b12b889d1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ingredients for vegan gardener&#39;s pie&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/gardeners-pie/full-pie-6d3bc293124a7d547784fa72dd4b2e395bed9c75b825684902de0630ceabb93a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vegan Gardener&#39;s Pie&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/gardeners-pie/served-850b92f956196bb2031bca11a2d39180fa8c015e6b455bab8515bb9cfa8b2898.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vegan Gardener&#39;s Pie&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/gardeners-pie/thumbnail-643a59b9b418f6c9665112dcc8a46858aeecf323b25f203eba4f21fdb71ef773.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vegan Gardener&#39;s Pie&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be the first to admit that I love potatoes. This gardeners pie is topped with a thick layer of creamy mashed potatoes, with a golden brown top. It’s to die for! Gardener’s pie (shepard’s pie for us veg folk) is filled with all the delicious ingredients that a gardener would have ready this time of year. You will love the flavor of the parsnips in this dish (and everything else).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing better than a home cooked meal from scratch. Although this recipe takes a lot of time it is well worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gardeners-pie&quot;&gt;Gardener’s Pie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe by: Hannah&lt;br /&gt;
Serves: 6&lt;br /&gt;
Prep time: 15 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Cook time: 45 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Total time: 1 hour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 med russet potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup plant based milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp nutritional yeast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 med onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 carrots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 parsnips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 stalk celery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup pearl barley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cups vegetable broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp rosemary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 tsp pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350°. Bring a large pot of water to a boil while you peel and quarter potatoes. Once water is boiling, add potatoes and boil for 15 minutes, or until very soft. Drain potatoes and return them to the pot. Add the plant based milk, nutritional yeast, and salt and pepper to taste. Mash potatoes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop onion, carrots, parsnips, and celery, then add to a hot cast iron pot. Cook for 5 minutes (if vegetables begin to stick, add a splash of water), then add garlic cook for 2 more minutes. Add pearl barley, broth, thyme, and rosemary, simmer 25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir in flour. If your pot is dry at the bottom add 2-5 Tbsp water. The barley will continue to absorb water in the oven. Spread mashed potatoes over the top of the barley mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place pot in heated oven and cook for 30 minutes. To make the top extra golden, turn your oven to broil and cook 3-5 more minutes. Watch carefully so it doesn’t burn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Stuffed Acorn Squash</title><link href="http://plateofplants.com/stuffed-acorn-squash" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stuffed Acorn Squash" /><published>2016-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/stuffed-acorn-squash</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://plateofplants.com/stuffed-acorn-squash">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/stuffed-acorn-squash/tempeh-stuffed-259e6155d9bfa28d641d7264bdb2fceb44843b099507114cb44e65e3e200b5a4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Acorn squash filled with tempeh sausage.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/stuffed-acorn-squash/served-709d2c8f533159984e554aabc77b439a8f98a9f7c6d58800f9bd5d7c820dfa07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Acorn squash filled with tempeh sausage and simple homemade stuffing.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/stuffed-acorn-squash/two-squash-2ec9df882fc799dc231b0b26a2e7e1db30925d64893055408f83fb5bcc8f3ed8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Acorn squash filled with tempeh sausage and simple homemade stuffing.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/stuffed-acorn-squash/close-up-341c98a2f800d46053ad478614a377686dc6371b478a721fd0cbc935a22c4a75.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Acorn squash filled with tempeh sausage and simple homemade stuffing.&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acorn squash are like natures little bowls. They are the perfect shape to stuff full of your holiday favorites. I chose to fill mine with a delicious sausage spiced tempeh, topped with some simple homemade stuffing. This recipe has so many spices and herbs added to it that it is extremely flavorful, without adding any oil. There is no need to use fat to add flavor when you have an arsenal of spices ready to go! This is truly a healthy holiday meal you can feel good about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stuffed-acorn-squash&quot;&gt;Stuffed Acorn Squash&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe by: Hannah&lt;br /&gt;
Serves: 4&lt;br /&gt;
Prep time: 30 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Cook time: 18 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Total time: 48 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 acorn squash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 oz package tempeh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Tbsp fresh sage, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp each: fennel seeds, garlic powder, paprika, chili powder, oregano, thyme, marjoram&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 flax egg (1 Tbsp flax meal + 2 1/2 Tbsp water)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stuffing&quot;&gt;Stuffing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 stalks celery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 Tbsp fresh sage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp fresh thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Tbsp fresh rosemary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 cups bread cubes, dried (see notes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-1 1/2 cups broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350°. Cut squash in half and scoop out seeds. Cut a little off the bottom of each half so it can sit flat. Place on parchment paper lined baking sheet and bake 20 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While squash is in the oven, make the tempeh sausage. Chop the tempeh and add it to a small bowl along with sage, fennel seeds, garlic powder, paprika, chili powder, oregano, thyme, marjoram, salt, and flax egg.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After 20 minutes remove squash from oven and fill 3/4 full with tempeh mixture. Return to oven for another 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make your stuffing. Heat a pot over medium heat. Add onion and celery and cook for 5-7 minutes until soft. Add herbs and bread cubes, stir. Slowly pour in broth until bread has fully absorbed and not dry anywhere. Season with salt and pepper to taste.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove squash from the oven. Fill with stuffing until heaping. Return to the oven for 20 more minutes. Let cool and enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use two small acorn squash that won’t get filled as full.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To dry your bread cubes: Heat your oven to 200° and place cubes on a baking sheet. Place in oven and check every 5 minutes. When they feel completely dry they are ready.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Pumpkin Gnocchi with Sage Cashew Cream</title><link href="http://plateofplants.com/pumpkin-gnocchi" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pumpkin Gnocchi with Sage Cashew Cream" /><published>2016-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/pumpkin-gnocchi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://plateofplants.com/pumpkin-gnocchi">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/pumpkin-gnocchi/ingredients-a609e8e3e95030aec48ffc1330db5200a35c349a78e2568d30b29fdae57db769.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ingredients for pumpkin gnocchi with sage cashew cream.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/pumpkin-gnocchi/sliced-gnocchi-f63e103f01273d5a5e0a57b992a440296004641b60d79a0c4e7bd10708051adf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cutting homemade pumpkin gnocchi.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/pumpkin-gnocchi/sauted-gnocchi-ff9e8a4f0fbaf52e78d8f3fbfa646c636356053d0f32e07fd51de4e34771328a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Delicious homemade pumpkin gnocchi.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/pumpkin-gnocchi/thumbnail-3592ad4bf1db173eaf20a77583652a0811bc45c3a46632f7db0a1ce8623900bd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Gnocchi with Sage Cashew Cream.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/pumpkin-gnocchi/two-bowls-6132067d6d3ed527ec6e5cab1cd34349cd88e4ca04765864722796a6e8ae9fa3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Gnocchi with Sage Cashew Cream.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think about November, I think about sage. Sage is one of my favorite herbs. It is the heart of Thanksgiving flavors. When I smell a sage leaf I am transported back to my mothers kitchen years ago. Food has such a way of bringing back memories and moments. Let Thanksgiving be a reminder of all the great times you have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These pumpkin gnocchi will make you feel like a master of holiday cooking. Homemade gnocchi taste so much better than store bought and you only need 4 ingredients. Although they take some extra time, it is totally worth it and they are really fun to make with friends and family. This recipe is made with all whole food ingredients. It’s a hearty meal that everyone will love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pumpkin-gnocchi-with-sage-cashew-cream&quot;&gt;Pumpkin Gnocchi with Sage Cashew Cream&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe by: Hannah&lt;br /&gt;
Serves: 6&lt;br /&gt;
Prep time: 30 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Cook time: 18 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Total time: 48 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gnocchi&quot;&gt;Gnocchi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 medium russet potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup pumpkin puree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-3 cups whole wheat flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cashew-cream&quot;&gt;Cashew Cream&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup cashews (soaked in water overnight)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 lemon, juiced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup nutritional yeast flakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 medium leaves sage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 grinds pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;everything-else&quot;&gt;Everything Else&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 shallots, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;small sage leaves for garnish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring a large pot of water to a boil. Peel and quarter potatoes. Add them into boil water and let cook 15 mins, until tender.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl mash potatoes and pumpkin together. Add in salt and flour 1/2 cup at a time. I used about 2 1/2 cups flour, but it will depend on how moist your potato pumpkin mash is. You know you have added enough flour when it feels like dough and you can mold it with our it sticking to your hands.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take 1/4 of the gnocchi dough and roll it into a rope approximately 1 inch wide. Flatten the rope it slightly with you hands. Cut every 1/2 inch. Repeat with the rest of the dough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring a fresh pot of water to a boil. once boiling add in gnocchi (you will need to do multiple batches). Cook gnocchi 3 minutes, or until they have floated to the top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While gnocchi are cooking, add all cashew cream ingredients to a high speed blender and blend for 30 seconds. Adjust seasonings to your liking and heat in a small saucepan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat a large skillet over medium heat. Add garlic and shallot, cook 2 minutes, stirring frequently. Add in gnocchi and sauté until lightly browned.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour sauce over gnocchi and serve, garnished with a small sage leaf.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Vegan Calico Beans</title><link href="http://plateofplants.com/vegan-calico-beans" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vegan Calico Beans" /><published>2016-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/vegan-calico-beans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://plateofplants.com/vegan-calico-beans">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/vegan-calico-beans/three-beans-35e71ee660792646f951d8089f9b134c41df414a0a67c3f5de2e92af77048085.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Navy beans, kidney beans, and black beans used for vegan calico beans.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/vegan-calico-beans/ingredients-3569053edea355a41a647adfdced5b08f404683caa5bdfddad727aebd09cab4f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vegan calico beans ingredients.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/vegan-calico-beans/served-beans-4d20c32196a514a5559577a437d381929a0fdda8125ff0003a539083a2f2b112.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vegan Calico Beans.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/vegan-calico-beans/table-833494ad236a5f8bf9d6ed04fb7a4dd0ae8d1fde8543ac4f535c0e52c3286470.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vegan Calico Beans.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my greatest cooking inspirations is my dear Grandma. From a very young age most of my memories involving food and cooking took place in her kitchen. My Grandma certainly loved to spoil us with treats like her delicious peach pie. Anyone who came over for dinner was treated to a homemade feast. Before I could see over the counter, I remember standing on a stool and helping her measure ingredients. This recipe is in honor of my Grandma who was laid to rest this past week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calico beans was one of her favorite recipes. Anyone who knew my grandma knew that she added sugar to everything, so it’s no surprise these beans are quite sweet, except instead I used maple syrup to sweeten it &lt;strong&gt;naturally&lt;/strong&gt;. I also made the recipe vegan by using tofu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell me in the comments below if you tried it out, and don’t forget to subscribe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calico-beans&quot;&gt;Calico Beans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe by: Hannah&lt;br /&gt;
Serves: 6&lt;br /&gt;
Prep time: 10 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Cook time: 45 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Total time: 55 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can (15 oz) black beans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can (15 oz) navy beans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can (15 oz) kidney beans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 medium onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 Tbsp apple cider vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp dry mustard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 tsp pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 12 oz package tofu, pressed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp liquid smoke&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tbsp nutritional yeast flakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tbsp tamari (or soy sauce)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350°.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crumble tofu into a medium size bowl. Add liquid smoke, yeast flakes, and tamari. Stir and set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl mix together tomato paste, maple syrup, apple cider vinegar, water, mustard, salt, and pepper. Stir thoroughly, until well combine. Add in drained and rinsed beans, onion, and tofu mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 45 minutes. Let cool 10 minutes before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Fresh Fiesta Tacos</title><link href="http://plateofplants.com/fresh-fiesta-tacos" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fresh Fiesta Tacos" /><published>2016-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/fresh-fiesta-tacos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://plateofplants.com/fresh-fiesta-tacos">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/fresh-fiesta-tacos/thumbnail-f20393c6952f4c2d3364684ea429479eeb1713e2099b4f13032afc995026e3bb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fresh fiesta tacos.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/fresh-fiesta-tacos/table-tacos-44d7b5da3234e6b1604dda2a006f509aa55836303260e40408d17e141c8dba16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fresh fiesta tacos.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/fresh-fiesta-tacos/row-of-tacos-f7434ff64a348faca87cd2de4f5590761165c6f4d76a014f7fb979efb937b9a4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fresh fiesta tacos.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;826&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrate this taco Tuesday in style. Impress your friends, family, and even yourself by making these tacos completely from scratch. Imagine homemade tortillas stuffed full of refried black beans, fiesta rice, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://plateofplants.com/chunky-guacamole&quot;&gt;chunky guacamole&lt;/a&gt;. Is your mouth watering yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have never made your own tortillas, it is time to start. They are so easy and simple to make. Homemade tortillas are made from masa, water, and salt. That is all you need. You will be wondering why you ever ate the ultra-processed store bought varieties. In this recipe I cook my tortillas in the oven, although it is traditional to cook them on the stovetop. I did this to avoid using oil. No oil was used in the making of this recipe. That means you can feel great about eating a meal filled with only nutritious whole foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fresh-fiesta-tacos&quot;&gt;Fresh Fiesta Tacos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe by: Hannah&lt;br /&gt;
Serves: 3&lt;br /&gt;
Prep time: 10 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Cook time: 15 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Total time: 25 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tortillas&quot;&gt;Tortillas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups masa harina&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 cups water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;refried-black-beans&quot;&gt;Refried Black Beans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 14 oz. can black beans, drained and rinsed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-3 tbsp vegetable broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp chili powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp onion powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fiesta-rice&quot;&gt;Fiesta Rice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 cups cooked brown rice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup salsa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-toppings&quot;&gt;Additional Toppings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://plateofplants.com/chunky-guacamole&quot;&gt;chunky guacamole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fajita vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;corn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;shredded lettuce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chopped cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;make-tortillas&quot;&gt;Make Tortillas:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl mix together all ingredients. Add more water, one tablespoon at a time if dough seems too dry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divide the dough into 8 equally sized balls. Cut a gallon sized zipper bag down the sides. Place one of the balls of dough in the center of the plastic bag. Press under a heavy cast iron pot, or a tortilla press if you have one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place pressed tortillas in a single layer on a parchment lined baking sheet. Bake at 375° for 7 minutes, flip, and bake another 7 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you remove the tortillas from the oven, immediately stack them up and wrap them in a dish towel. This allows them to steam, and maintain their flexibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;make-tacos&quot;&gt;Make Tacos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat a cast iron skillet over medium heat. Add garlic and cook until browned, about 2 minutes. Add the black beans, spices, and broth, let cook 2 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mash the mixture to desired consistency. Add more broth if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add cooked brown rice and salsa to a pan and warm over medium heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assemble tacos by spooning refried black beans and fiesta rice onto a fresh tortilla. Finish with additional toppings and a squeeze of lime juice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Chunky Guacamole</title><link href="http://plateofplants.com/chunky-guacamole" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chunky Guacamole" /><published>2016-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/chunky-guacamole</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://plateofplants.com/chunky-guacamole">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/chunky-guacamole/text-f0a9f738203f189875c11e1366ffe6402690e63793728d9ddd4e39d4f095bace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chunky guacamole.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/chunky-guacamole/ingredients-4b0b24a4256a388ba73d9279e4b57216676fcceebcbaca51a32a400620eff0de.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ingredients for chunky guacamole.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/chunky-guacamole/served-guac-d9244fedd08f65ae147d8f1fe5f0d9408356d6592183d8c0b76301f024231502.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chunky guacamole.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making guacamole at home is as easy as cutting up a few vegetables and mixing them in a bowl together. It only takes a couple minutes.  Plus, it’s more affordable then store bought varieties, which often have added processed ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make this recipe a few times a week because I put it on everything! It’s perfect as a dip, or to put on top of all your favorite food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chunky-guacamole&quot;&gt;Chunky Guacamole&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe by: Hannah&lt;br /&gt;
Serves: 2&lt;br /&gt;
Prep time: 3 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Cook time: 0 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Total time: 3 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 avocados, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 roma tomato, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup chopped red onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 lime, juiced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup cilantro, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix together all ingredients. Season with salt and pepper to taste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Pomegranate Power Salad</title><link href="http://plateofplants.com/pomegranate-power-salad" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pomegranate Power Salad" /><published>2016-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/pomegranate-power-salad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://plateofplants.com/pomegranate-power-salad">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/pomegranate-power-salad/ingredients-85ebe94762b8d8746d280eb2ca6fa04149fae05e40dc7238c7d39d9be3f18d18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot; Ingredients for pomegranate power salad.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/pomegranate-power-salad/salad-bowl-05638cffbd6bdc9bae5e30e88d5fe2b4761b68f2e918adb98de64c9a7c8b8424.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pomegranate Power Salad.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/pomegranate-power-salad/two-bowls-c51ecb9aaa8f943bd911620c04a03beb89466991d351e160db8d77c7f3254944.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pomegranate Power Salad.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week Bryce and I went on a little getaway to Asheville, NC.   It was beautiful, but anytime we travel we tend to eat food that isn’t the healthiest. So the time has come for a power salad. This power salad is made to rejuvenate your body. It’s a perfect way to start your week. These ingredients are crazy good for you. It has:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kale - packed full of vitamins A, C, K&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pomegranate - high in potassium, and vitamins C, K, B6&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avocado - loaded with vitamin K, folate, and potassium&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon - full of vitamin C&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ginger - good source of vitamin C, magnesium, potassium, copper and manganese&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walnuts - high in manganese, copper, and vitamin B6&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that’s what I call power food! Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pomegranate-power-salad&quot;&gt;Pomegranate power salad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe by: Hannah&lt;br /&gt;
Serves: 2&lt;br /&gt;
Prep time: 15 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Cook time: 10 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Total time: 25 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup pomegranate seeds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 cups kale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 avocado&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup cucumber&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 lemon, juiced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp grated ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp agave nectar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;walnut-parmesan&quot;&gt;Walnut Parmesan&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup walnuts, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tbsp nutritional yeast flakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 300°.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wash the kale by filling a large bowl with water and immersing the kale in it, stirring it around with your hands (this method removes dirt better than running water). Remove stems, chop, and add to a large bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small bowl mix lemon juice, water, ginger, agave nectar, and soy sauce. Pour over kale and using your hands, massage, to soften the kale. Place in fridge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place chopped walnuts in a fine mesh strainer, and run under cold water for 30 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix together the walnuts (still wet), nutritional yeast, garlic powder, and salt.  Spread over a parchment lined baking sheet and cook 8-10 mins, until toasted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take kale out of fridge. Add chunks of cucumber, avocado, pomegranate seeds, and walnut parmesan. Mix together and serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Loaded Sweet Potatoes</title><link href="http://plateofplants.com/loaded-sweet-potatoes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Loaded Sweet Potatoes" /><published>2016-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://plateofplants.com/loaded-sweet-potatoes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://plateofplants.com/loaded-sweet-potatoes">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/loaded-sweet-potatoes/ingredients-46c251cc925d8fe6dc304e97fdbd2cc8cc0f2fc88be465c5dc7ac2dd4de4c71c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ingredients for loaded sweet potatoes.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/loaded-sweet-potatoes/before-baked-5e169b925878d62fbb3ce1e1b3ce027deafc28688534bfe804b5c7cc8ca26e9e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sweet potatoes ready to be baked.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/loaded-sweet-potatoes/after-baked-de854df952b595a46f3f1e4c6ff6effbbb9029ead7399bce2fc9b4a113c853c1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sweet potatoes that have been baked.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/loaded-sweet-potatoes/black-beans-added-46ee7c94bfd7d0dd427311a17937186d0874bf0aa3c34011d2b13bc6f44622e1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Baked sweet potatoes filled with black beans.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;366&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/loaded-sweet-potatoes/jicama-slaw-accc3bb1e20c3cfa1abce9deb85144bbd822307b045769e3d153119d23166cce.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jicama slaw.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/loaded-sweet-potatoes/loaded-overhead-9e7c2da2ba4c9df0f96b7afcfe6eb0939c227337147aaed6f6bd2c0cea00b462.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Delicious loaded sweet potatoes.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/loaded-sweet-potatoes/loaded-67917eb191aa5e853172fa9b1f785c88fdd867579a22441975f859e66bf8cc4d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Delicious loaded sweet potatoes.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/loaded-sweet-potatoes/plated-af65059d60043a90141a8c55857cee9810b7917c009ad475749523c8f40c89da.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A plate of loaded sweet potatoes.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://plateofplants.github.io/assets/loaded-sweet-potatoes/dinner-table-fd87776e591010241c05e93b7703a66f5456744c3cd567c41f5e2cba42a0743d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dinner table of loaded sweet potatoes.&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;367&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who doesn’t love a sweet potato? The more you eat them the more you’ll love them. Sweet potatoes taste amazing on their own and they barely even need salt. With the addition of more fresh ingredients you can have a super easy, satisfying, and healthy dinner. This meal is made from all whole foods. When you cook this way you’ll feel great about what you’re eating and you’ll have way more energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ingredient I’ve recently started using is jicama. I can’t believe I had never used it before this season! Jicama is such a versatile ingredient because it is great cooked or raw. I feel like jicama tastes like a mix between an apple and a potato. In this recipe I used it in a raw jicama slaw on top of the loaded sweet potatoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These sweet potatoes are best when they are served with avocado. The creamy texture and flavor makes it that much better. I usually pile avocado on top of the jicama slaw and eat it all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;loaded-sweet-potatoes&quot;&gt;Loaded Sweet Potatoes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recipe by: Hannah&lt;br /&gt;
Serves: 4&lt;br /&gt;
Prep time: 5 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Cook time: 35 minutes&lt;br /&gt;
Total time: 40 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 sweet potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 15 oz can black beans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup jicama&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cup red onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup cilantro, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 lime, juiced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 avocado&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350°. Slice sweet potatoes in half lengthwise, and place cut side down on parchment lined baking sheet. Bake 25-30 min, until tender. Remove and let cool 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While sweet potatoes are baking, drain and rinse black beans. Mix black beans, garlic powder, cumin, salt, and pepper together in a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once potatoes have cooled, carefully flip them over, so they are skin side down. Using a fork score and mash the potato. Try to open the potato up so there is room for the beans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill the sweet potatoes with the black beans, and return to the oven for 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the potatoes bake, prepare the jicama slaw. Slice jicama into matchsticks and slice onion very thin. In a bowl stir together jicama, onion, cilantro, lime juice, and salt and pepper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a spatula to press down on each sweet potato. This flattens them so you can now pile on the jicama slaw.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with sliced avocado on the side or right on top!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Hannah Schoenborn</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary></summary></entry></feed>
